A Software Developer with experience in the design, development, testing, and maintenance of software. Possessing diverse skill set with proficiency in various platforms and languages. Dedicated to continuous self-development, enjoys working closely with others, and has an eye for detail and identifying problems.

CONTACT



LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/pratyakshajha



Email

hello@pratyakshajha.me



Website

pratyakshajha.me



Phone

+91 9146502182

SKILLS

JAVA

Core Java, Spring, Spring boot, JPA, JSF, Struts, JSP

SQL

DB2, MySQL, Oracle

AWS

AWS CDK, SAM, Serverless

PYTHON

scripting, web – flask, django, Data – numpy, pandas, dask, ML – sklearn, keras, pytorch

OTHERS

Docker, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript – Angular framework, Agile methodology

PROJECTS

Covid vaccine slot finder – An angular based UI to display data from Cowin API

pratyakshajha.me – A hugo based website for blogging

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recipient of Deep Learning Nanodegree Scholarship from Facebook
- Data Science for Executives a set of verified courses by edx.org on Statistics, ML and Basics of IoT

PRATYAKSHA JHA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Principal Global Services

JULY, 2019 - PRESENT

- · Java and AWS developer in Finance team for cash management applications.
- These applications range from printing checks, sending and receiving payments, financial data to and from various banks, and complying with government regulations. These apps support the treasury at the enterprise level thereby enabling the sister companies to make timely payments to their customers.
- Heading the team in migration of these applications from current code base to the cloud (AWS).
- Driven and adaptable, being the first few to start with migration. This involved getting familiar with cloud platforms, oversaw initial setups and form standard processes.
- Delivered a major IT migration, due to an acquisition, with the highest quality and on time.
- Introduced processes and best practices that enhanced coding standards, release processes and improved coordination with home office counterparts.
- Known for excellent troubleshooting skills identify root cause and deliver timely, responsive and effective solutions.
- Strong domain knowledge and team player, hence being the go-to person for major issues and on boarding new members.
- Fueled innovation through initiatives like code jams and POC Fridays.
- Consistently rated highly successful, with a rising star award in 2020.

INTERN

RobonomicsAl

JUN, 2018 - JUL, 2018

- Worked on Image labeling step required for data preparation in image classification algorithm.
- Built an extraction-based text summarization solution aimed at summarizing Government notices.

Visvesvaraya National Institute of Technology JUN, 2017 – JUL, 2017

- Learnt probability theory in depth random variables and multivariate random variables.
- · Studied noise in communication systems, their estimation and simulation.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications
Engineering 2015 - 2019

Shri Ramdeobaba College of Engineering and Management, Nagpur